weightlossresources.co.uk 2019-04-12

# Privacy and Cookies Policy - Weight Loss Resources

**This policy was last updated 26th May 2018 and further changes will be communicated by updating this page**

## Who We Are

Weight Loss Resources Ltd (wlr) is a company registered in the United Kingdom, owner of this website www.weightlossresources.co.uk - our full contact details are at the bottom of this page.

At wlr, we are committed to maintaining the trust and confidence of our members, subscribers and visitors to our web site. In particular, we want you to know that wlr does not sell, rent or trade email lists or any other contact information with other businesses for marketing purposes.

We've tried to make this privacy policy as easy to use as possible whilst providing you with enough detail to ensure you are fully informed. If you have any questions about this policy or any other privacy issues, please contact helpteam@weightlossresources.co.uk we'll be happy to help.

## Information we collect and why

### Members

When you sign up to become a member of wlr (either a free trial or paid membership), you are entering into a contract with us.

In order that we can provide you with the service we will ask you to provide some personal information such as;

  * Full Name
  * Age
  * Weight and height
  * Sex
  * Email address

If you become a paid member we will collect further information such as:

  * Postal Address
  * Telephone Number
  * Payment card details

In order to undertake service personalisation, we will also gather information about the device(s) you use to access our site, and some of the pages you visit. For further information on our use of cookies and tracking please see our Cookie Policy below.

Throughout your membership we will collect information related to your weight and use of the wlr tools in order for you to use the tools effectively, and to help you reach and/or maintain your weight goals.

### Shop Customers

When you order goods from wlr shop you are entering in to a contract with us.

In order that we can provide with your products we will ask you to provide personal information such as:

  * Full name
  * Postal address
  * Email address
  * Telephone number
  * Payment card details

We use cookies to collect information on the device you are using, to make your shopping basket work, and some of the pages that you visit on our site. This means that if you do return and subscribe or become a member at a future date we may use information stored in cookies we have set as part of the personal information we collect. For further information on our use of cookies and tracking please see our Cookie Policy below.

### Subscribers

If you only subscribe to our newsletter, or other communications, the personal information we collect is limited to:

  * First name
  * Email address
  * Some of the pages you visited on our website. For further information on our use of cookies and tracking please see our Cookie Policy below.

This information allows us to provide the communication you requested, and helps us personalise these communications. You can opt out of receiving these communications at any time and the opportunity to do this is included with all these communications.

### Visitors

If you only vist our website and don't become a subscriber or member we don't collect any personal data from you, however we do use cookies to collect information on the device you are using and some of the pages that you visit on our site.

This means that if you do return and subscribe or become a member at a future date we may use information stored in cookies we have set as part of the personal information we collect.

For further information on our use of cookies and tracking please see our Cookie Policy below.

### Combination of wlr services you have used

Many wlr users have used more than one of the above services. In this case we will try to gather your information into one 'client record'.

Only information collected directly by wlr, as described above, is used to compile this record. We do not collect personally identifiable information about you from other sources.

The purpose of gathering this information together is to provide appropriate service and support and to maintain the integrity and accuracy of our database and to help prevent duplication, particularly of communications.

## How we use your information

In line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) we must have a legal basis for processing your personal information. The legal bases we rely on at wlr are:

**Contract** \- your personal information is processed in order to provide services and/or goods to you.

**Consent** – where you have not entered into a contract with us but agree to us using your information to provide you with communications from us such as our newsletter.

**Legitimate Interests** \- this means the interests of wlr in managing our business to allow us to provide users with the best services and products we can in the most secure and appropriate way, and to attract and retain customers.

**Legal Obligation** – where there is statutory or other legal requirement to share the information e.g. when we have to share your information for law enforcement purposes.

Here is a list of the ways that we may use your personal information, and which of the reasons described above we rely on to do so. Where we list legitimate interests as a reason, we also give a brief description of what the legitimate interests are.

Purpose of Using Information | Legal Basis | Description of Legitimate Interests  
---|---|---  
Provide wlr membership service | Contract | n/a  
Process membership packs and/or orders | Contract | n/a  
Notify you of your membership details and status | Contract / Legitimate Interests | Helping you to use wlr and make the best of your wlr membership  
Notify you of order status | Contract / Legitimate Interests | Keeping you informed, ensuring efficient service  
Provide customer service | Contract / Legitimate Interests | Handling customer service effectively, keeping records up to date  
Website personalisation and administration | Legitimate Interests | Developing services and applications that attract and retain customers. Improving user interface and functionality of our site  
Marketing communications to inform you of promotions Provide you with online advertising | Legitimate Interests | Attracting and retaining customers, improving interaction with our site  
Notifying you about enhancements to our services, such as changes to the website and new services that may be of interest to you. | Legitimate Interests | Developing services and applications that attract and retain customers. Improving user interface and functionality of our site  
Contact you to undertake customer satisfaction surveys, invite you to provide product reviews or for market research. | Legitimate Interests | Developing products, services and applications that attract and retain customers, Improving interaction with our site  
Maintaining network and data security | Legal Obligation / Legitimate Interests | To maintain the security of our network and the safety and confidentiality of personal information.  
Demand forecasting, management information and research | Legitimate Interests | We use information about products bought and volumes, to help us to plan for supplying demand, and develop products  
  
## Who we share your information with and why

We work with a number of trusted suppliers and businesses in order to provide goods and services. The categories of third parties with whom we share your data are:

**Delivery Companies** \- In order for you to receive your goods, we work with a number of delivery companies. We only pass enough information to them to facilitate delivery of your items.

**IT Companies** \- we work with business who support our website and other business systems.

**Payment processing** \- we work with trusted payment processing providers in order to securely take and manage payments

## Changes of business ownership and control

Weight Loss Resources may, from time to time, expand or reduce its business and this may involve the sale of certain divisions or the transfer of control of certain divisions to other parties.

Data provided by Users will, where it is relevant to any division so transferred, be transferred along with that division and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was supplied by you.

## How long we keep your information

As a paid member, all the information we hold for you will be kept for up to 24 months after your last interaction with us. During this period your information is retained so that you can reactivate your membership with your historical information if you choose to.

For all members, customers and subscribers, information in your client record (as described above) including a history of any financial transactions will be kept for 7 years after your last interaction with us.

## Your rights with regard to your personal information

You are entitled to request the following from wlr, these are called your Data Subject Rights and there is more information on these on the Information Commissioners website www.ico.org.uk

**Right of access** – to request access to your personal information and information about how we process it

**Right to rectification** – to have your personal information corrected if it is inaccurate

**Right to erasure** (also known as the Right to be Forgotten) – to have your personal information erased.

**Right to restriction of processing** – to restrict processing of your personal information

**Right to data portability** \- to electronically move, copy or transfer your personal information in a standard form

**Right to object** \- to object to processing of your personal information

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection regulator in Europe. The contact details for the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the data protection regulator in the UK, are available on the ICO website www.ico.org.uk However, we encourage you to contact us with any concerns you have and we will try to resolve any issues.

If you have any general questions about your rights, or want to exercise your rights, please contact helpteam@weightlossresources.co.uk

## Cookie Policy

This policy is designed to help you understand what cookies are, how wlr uses them and the control you have over their use.

By continuing to use www.weightlossresources.co.uk you are agreeing to our use of cookies in the manner described in this notice.

## What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer or other device when you visit the Site. This allows the Site to recognise you as a user either for the duration of your visit (using a ‘session cookie’) or for repeat visits ( a ‘persistent cookie’). They are not harmful and do not contain any information such as your home address, date of birth or credit card details.

The cookies we use fall into four broad types:

**Strictly Necessary Cookies**

These cookies are essential in helping you to move around the wlr site and use its features. Without these cookies, the tools and services on wlr would not work correctly . These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing.

**Analytical/Performance Cookies**

In order to keep the Site, its services and products relevant, easy to use and up-to-date, we use web analytics services to help us understand how people use our Site. For example, we can see which parts of the Site and products are most popular, identify when errors occur, and test different versions of a page or feature to see which one works best.

**Functionality Cookies**

These cookies allow websites and applications to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. The information these cookies collect is usually anonymised which means we can't identify you personally. They do not gather any information about you that could be used for selling advertising or remembering where you've been on the internet, but do help us to serve you with advertising that is more relevant to you.

**Targeted Marketing Cookies - Public Website Only**

(These cookies are not used in the members only (logged-in) areas of the site - and we do not carry any third party advertising on logged-in pages.)

In public areas of our site we use cookies to assist in targeted advertising. Without these cookies, online advertisements you encounter will be less relevant to you and your interests. We also use them to measure the effectiveness of our marketing communications, for example by telling us if you have responded to an advert that we have sent you.

If you would like more information on any of these types of Cookies, including how to opt-out, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

## What do we use Cookies for?

They enable you to use wlr tools and shop and enable wlr to give you a personalised web experience.

  * To allow you to securely sign in to your wlr account.
  * To recognise the device that you are using.
  * To store the content of your online shopping bag whilst you browse the site and to complete an order.
  * To record the areas of the wlr site that you have visited. We use this information to help make the website more user friendly and to continuously improve the quality of the service we provide.
  * To distribute visitors to wlr evenly across our servers to ensure the content is served at the fastest possible speed.
  * For re-marketing purposes to determine relevant related products to show you when you're browsing on other selected websites. These cookies can be associated with services provided by a third party such as an advertising network.

We also offer you the facility to share your experience on wlr through social media sites such as Facebook. By using these features, you are consenting to allow cookies from these providers. More information about how these providers use cookies can be found at their websites.

Cookies are an essential part of how the wlr site works, as they remember certain information about a visitor. We use First Party cookies (these are placed there and used solely by wlr) and Third Party cookies (these are placed there by third parties we work with).

## Are cookies safe?

Yes. The information stored in cookies is safe and anonymous to any external third party, and your account security is never compromised. You can find more information about cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). For a video about cookies visit [www.google.com/intl/en-GB/policies/technologies/cookies/](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies?hl=en-GB)

## Can I turn off cookies?

Yes – but if you choose not to allow the use of cookies, your experience of our Site will be limited and many integral aspects of the Site, including (but not limited to) adding items to your shopping bag and accessing your account, will not work at all.

To change your cookie settings, or if you want to be notified each time a cookie is about to be used, you should amend the settings provided in your web browser to prevent us from storing cookies on your computer hard drive.

For information on how to disable cookies, please consult the "Help" tab of your browser via the menu bar. For further information on non-essential cookies used for targeting and banner advertising please see below.

Details of our Third Party Cookies

wlr allows selected Third Parties who participate with us in marketing programs to place cookies when you visit our site. These cookies enable us to monitor which adverts you see and click on to get to our site.

For details of the Third Party cookies we use please see the table below. wlr is not responsible for the content or privacy policies of Third Parties or other websites, and we advise that you check these yourself.

The following Cookies are all used for Analytical and Targeting purposes:

  * Google Analytics
  * Bing Ads
  * DoubleClick
  * GA Audiences
  * Facebook Custom Audiences
  * Google Adsense (for more information on Google cookies see <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?gl=uk> )

## Opting Out

Website visitors who don’t want their data used by Google Analytics can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. To opt-out of Analytics for the web, visit the Google Analytics opt-out page and install the add-on for your browser. Learn more about the opt-out and how to properly install the browser add-on [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en-GB).

Visitors can also opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated)

## Our Contact Details

You can contact us with questions about privacy or to to exercise any of your personal information rights in the following ways:

Email: helpteam@weightlossresources.co.uk

Telephone: 01733 345592 (Monday to Friday 8am - 6pm)

Post: Weight Loss Resources, 2C Flag Business Exchange, Vicarage Farm Road, Peterborough, PW1 5TX

## Start a Free Trial Today 

Weight Loss Resources provides tools and information to control your weight by getting your calorie balance right and learning what suits you. You can take a free trial to access the databases, food diary and tools

Take our FREE trial »
